<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ch 2 - Hub and Branch VPN Connectivity on Fortinet FortiGate Technical Recipie- Azure SDWAN</title>
    <link>/02demo1.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ch 2 - Hub and Branch VPN Connectivity on Fortinet FortiGate Technical Recipie- Azure SDWAN</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language><atom:link href="/02demo1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Task 1 - FortiGate on Hub LB</title>
      <link>/02demo1/2_task1.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/02demo1/2_task1.html</guid>
      <description>Task 1 - Add the FortiGates to the Hub Load Balancer Backend Pool Select the Hub External Load Balancer sdwan-USERXX-workshop-hub1-elb1 Click on Backend pools Add FortiGate1 and FortiGate2 port1 interfaces and then click on Save 10.10.0.4
10.10.0.5</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Task 2 - LB Rules for VPN Traffic</title>
      <link>/02demo1/3_task2.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/02demo1/3_task2.html</guid>
      <description>Task 2 - Create load balancing rules for IPSEC VPN Traffic Select the Hub External Load Balancer sdwan-USERXX-workshop-hub1-elb1
Click on Load balancing rules
Create Load balancing rules for UDP 500 and UDP 4500 - one rule for each</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Task 3 - Hub and Spoke VPN Verification</title>
      <link>/02demo1/4_task3.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/02demo1/4_task3.html</guid>
      <description>Task 3 - Hub and Branch VPN Connectivity Verifications Verify that the FortiGates are responding to Azure Load Balancer Health Checks
Select the Hub External Load Balancer sdwan-USERXX-workshop-hub1-elb1
Click on Insights - Click the &amp;ldquo;Refresh&amp;rdquo; button a few times, eventually (~30 seconds) the FortiGate reachability will be indicated.
Verify that the VPN connections from the Branch to the Hub are UP
Verify that the BGP peering with the Hub is UP and that the Branch FortiGate learned the Hub and other Branches&amp;rsquo; CIDRs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 2 Quiz</title>
      <link>/02demo1/5_chapter2quiz.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/02demo1/5_chapter2quiz.html</guid>
      <description>Chapter 2 - QUIZ Why is one FortiGate depicted as unhealthy by the Azure Hub External Load Balancer?
Why is NAT used to access the FortiGates, but for IPSEC VPN traffic Load balancing rules are used?
Do FortiGates in the Branches learn Spoke11 and Spoke12 CIDRs?
Why is one FortiGate depicted as unhealthy by the Azure Hub External Load Balancer?
The passive FortiGate does not respond to the load balancer health probes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 2 Discussion</title>
      <link>/02demo1/6_ch2discussion.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/02demo1/6_ch2discussion.html</guid>
      <description>Discussion Points During a Dem - Chapter 2 When discussing load balanced traffic with the customer, point out key details about the Azure Load Balancers such as the following:
Azure LB uses 5-tuple hash for traffic distribution IPSec in an Active/Active configuration is not supported as session stability cannot be guaranteed to IkE rekeys, and deterministic IP termination. TCP/UDP headers are rewritten to the backend pool. HTTP/s headers are not changed.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
